Finding Aid for Penn Central Transportation Company Records 1835-1981
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Pennsylvania Railroad Company, 1847-1966; 83 linear feet
  - Pennsylvania Railroad Company: Subsidiaries
    - Traverse City Railroad Company
      - Minutes, 1871-1918 (Volume 134)
      - Minutes: Stockholders Annual Meetings, 1917-1918 (Box 243)
      - Reports to Interstate Commerce Commission
        - 1898-1909, 12 items (Box 243)
        - 1910-1917, 11 items (Box 244)
      - Reports to Michigan Board of Assessors
        - 1902-1904, 3 volumes (Box 244)
        - 1905-1917, 14 items (Box 245)
      - Reports to Michigan Railroad Commission
        - 1903-1906, 1909-1917; 14 items (Box 246)
    - Union Belt Railway of Detroit
      - Application to Interstate Commerce Commission, 1927 (Box 247)
      - Correspondence
        - Appointment of Economy Committee, 1934-1936 (Box 247)
        - Consolidation of Belt Offices with Joint Agency at Produce Terminal, 1932-1936 (Box 247)
        - Creation of New Engine District Number 5, 1928-1929 (Box 247)
        - Credit Union for Employees, 1930-1936 (Box 247)
        - Discipline of Employees, 1926-1927; 2 folders (Box 247)
        - Duplicate Service in Belt Territory, 1933-1935 (Box 247)
        - Engine house Facilities at Fullerton Avenue, 1927-1932 (Box 247)
        - Holden Branch, 1923-1940 (Box 247)
        - Operating Agreement with Wabash Railway Company, Pere Marquette Railway Company, and Pennsylvania Railroad Company, 1930-1935; 2 folders (Box 247)
        - Side Track Agreements for Industries on Union Belt, 1934-1937 (Box 247)
        - Twenty-first Street Engine House, 1925-1928; 1931; 2 folders (Box 247)
      - Stenographer's Minutes (Before the Interstate Commerce Commission), November 28, 1932 (Box 247)
- Miscellaneous Railroads Records, 6 linear feet
  This series contains records of railroads not based in Michigan, and is primarily annual reports and bylaws. Also included is a history of the St. Charles Air Line Railroad in Chicago. (Most of these records are duplicates of material sent to other repositories as part of the Penn Central Railroad Appraisal Project.)
  - Akron and Barberton Belt Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports, 1940; 1944-1945; 1951-1958 (Box 248)
  - Baltimore and Eastern Railroad Company
    - Bylaws and Organization, January 1924 (Box 248)
  - Baltimore, Chesapeake and Atlantic Railway Company
    - Annual Report, 1927 (Box 248)
  - Chicago and Alton Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports, 1910-1919; 4 folders (Box 248)
  - Chicago, Burlington and Quincy Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports, 1910-1919; 5 folders (Box 248)
  - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway Company
    - Annual Reports, 1910-1919; 3 folders (Box 248)
  - Chicago Union Station Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1916-1919, 1922-1924 (Box 248)
      - 1925-1926 (Box 248)
  - Cleveland and Pittsburgh Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1913-1920, 1922; 1926-1930 (Box 248)
      - 1931-1941, 1944-1945; 1951-1956 (Box 248)
  - Delaware Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1901, 1903 (Box 248)
      - 1908-1914, 1916-1919 (Box 248)
      - 1920-1921, 1923-1926; 1928; 1931; 1936; 1940-1941; 1944-1945; 1951-1956 (Box 248)
    - Proceedings of Annual Meeting, 1899; 1901 (Box 248)
  - Erie and Pittsburgh Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1911-1928 (Box 249)
      - 1929, 1940-1941; 1944-1945; 1951-1956 (Box 249)
  - Indianapolis Union Railway Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1915-1924 (Box 249)
      - 1925-1933, 1941; 1943-1944 (Box 249)
      - 1945, 1951-1956 (Box 249)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission
    - Specifications for Maps, Charts and Schedules of Telegraph and Telephone Properties Owned by Railroad, Telegraph, Cable, and Telephone Companies, 1917 (Box 249)
  - Kewaunee, Green Bay and Western Railroad Company
    - Reports to Interstate Commerce Commission, 1963-1968 (Box 290)
  - Lehigh Valley Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports, 1962 (Box 249)
  - Little Miami Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports, 1920-1929 (Box 249)
  - Logansport and Toledo Railway Company
    - Annual Reports, 1902-1904 (Box 249)
  - Long Island Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1902-1903 (Box 249)
      - 1907-1909, 1912-1913; 1922 (Box 249)
      - 1933-1935, 1939-1941; 1943-1945 (Box 249)
  - Monongahela Railway Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1922-1927, 1930-1933; 1939 (Box 249)
      - 1941-1944, 1947; 1951-1956; 1958 (Box 249)
  - Northern Central Railway Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1879-1881 (Box 249)
      - 1882-1884 (Box 249)
      - 1886-1888 (Box 249)
      - 1889-1891 (Box 250)
      - 1892-1894 (Box 250)
      - 1895-1899 (Box 250)
      - 1900-1905 (Box 250)
      - 1908-1909, 1911-1912 (Box 250)
      - 1913-1917, 1919-1920 (Box 250)
      - 1921-1926, 1928-1930; 1932-1933; 1936; 1939; 1941-1944; 1951-1954; 1956 (Box 250)
    - Bylaws and Organization, March 1, 1906 (Box 250)
  - Pennsylvania General Transit Company - Trucking: Grand Rapids, MI, 1928-1930 (Box 290)
  - Pennsylvania Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1880-1882, 1 volumes (Box 251)
      - 1883-1886, 1 volumes (Box 251)
      - 1887-1897, 1 volumes (Box 251)
      - 1898-1903, 1 volumes (Box 251)
      - 1904, 1906-1907 (Box 251)
      - 1908-1912 (Box 251)
      - 1913-1917 (Box 251)
      - 1918-1926, 1931-1933; 1935; 1937 (Box 251)
      - 1939, 1941-1944; 1951-1954; 1956 (Box 251)
  - Pennsylvania-Reading Seashore Lines
    - Annual Report, 1939; 1952-1956; 1958 (Box 252)
  - Pere Marquette Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports, 1906-1917; 5 folders (Box 252)
  - Pere Marquette Railway Company
    - Annual Reports, 1917-1919; 2 folders (Box 252)
  - Philadelphia, Baltimore and Washington Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports, 1918-1919; 1921; 1925-1927; 1929-1930; 1932-1933; 1939; 1944; 1951-1956 (Box 252)
    - Bylaws and Organization, 1912; 1913; 1917 (Box 252)
  - Philadelphia, Wilmington and Baltimore Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports, 1890; 1896; 1899 (Box 252)
  - Pittsburgh and Lake Erie Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports, 1966; 1973 (Box 252)
  - Pittsburgh, Chartiers and Youghiogheny Railway Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1906-1916 (Box 252)
      - 1917-1928 (Box 252)
      - 1928-1934 (Box 252)
  - Pittsburgh, Youngstown and Ashtabula Railway Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1906-1908, 1910-1911; 1914-1919; 1925-1927 (Box 253)
      - 1929-1930, 1939; 1941; 1944; 1951-1956 (Box 253)
  - Richmond-Washington Company
    - Annual Reports, 1924-1927; 1929-1930; 1942; 1952-1956; 1958 (Box 253)
  - Saint Charles Air Line Railroad
    - History of the Saint Charles Air Line Railroad in Chicago, 1902 (Box 253)
  - Union Depot Company (Columbus, Ohio)
    - Annual Reports
      - 1917-1930 (Box 253)
      - 1944, 1950-1956; 1958 (Box 253)
  - United New Jersey Railroad and Canal Company
    - Annual Report, 1958 (Box 253)
  - West Jersey and Seashore Railroad Company
    - Annual Reports
      - 1899-1905 (Box 253)
      - 1905-1910 (Box 253)
      - 1911-1912, 1914-1920 (Box 253)
      - 1922-1928, 1930-1931; 1933; 1944; 1950-1952; 1954-1956 (Box 253)
    - Bylaws and Organization, 1899-1900; 1902; 1904; 1906 (Box 253)